Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.10.31 10:53:52
-=The Last Fantasy=-
翻译:herbalmin，accnk，juarez 校对:岁月倒影
Justin.
I just thought I'd stop by and say goodbye.
I heard you were going back to Smallville tomorrow.
Yeah, Smallville.
How's it going?
You tell me.
You've been here five months. You've come a long way.
Your body has done a lot of healing.
Except for my hands.
They'll never get better and I'll never draw again...
...and that's the only thing I was ever good at.
You suffer severe nerve damage. It's lucky you have movement in your hands.
-I did everything I could, you know that. -Really?
Is that what you told the five patients who filed malpractice suits against you?
Now, I can understand your still being angry...
...but blaming me isn't gonna change your condition.
You were in an accident and you have to accept that.
I was in a hit-and-run.
You know, when I was your age, I wanted to be a violinist.
So I applied to the Conservatory, but I failed the audition.
The instructor told me that I had the hands of a surgeon...
...and that's why I moved into medicine.
As one door closes...
...another one opens.
You're young, you'll find something new.
Goodbye, Justin.
Have a nice life, Dr. Wells.
Rene, honey, I'm sorry.
-Another ungrateful patient? -Aren't they all?
-So you think he'll sue? -He doesn't have any proof.
He's alive, he should be thanking me.
What's going on?
You okay?
Get us out of here! Hurry up! Come on!
Get us out of here now. Get us out of here now! Hurry up! Come on!
-Help! -Help us!
That's it.
-Give me a hand up. -All right.
Okay, grab my hands.
片名:超人前传
主题曲《Save me》:谁来拯救我
领衔主演：汤姆・威灵
让你温暖的手伸出驱散我的痛苦
主演:克丽斯汀・克鲁克
谁来拯救我
主演:迈克尔・罗森巴姆
我不在乎你是怎么做到
主演：埃里克・约翰森
只要你留下，和我在一起
主演：山姆・琼斯三世
快来吧，我一直在等待着你
主演：艾利森・麦克
主演：安妮特・奥图尔
第十九集:毁坏
约翰・施耐得 饰演 强纳森・肯特
我一直留着整个世界只为你闪耀
超人始创作者:杰瑞・希杰尔和乔・夏斯特
留下，留下
快出现吧
电视策划:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
（大都会儿童医院）
贾斯丁
我想顺道过来道个别
我听说你准备明天回斯摩维尔
是的，斯摩维尔
怎么样了？
你说呢
你来了五个月，有了很大的进展
你的身体恢复得很好
除了我的手
它们不能恢复了 我也不能再画画…
…而画画是我唯一的特长
你遭受了严重的神经损伤 你的手可以动已经很幸运了
- 我尽了最大的努力，你懂的 - 真的吗？
五个病人起诉你医疗过失的时候 你也是这么说的吗？
我能理解你仍然很生气…
…但是责备我也不会改变你的现状
你出了事故，而你必须接受它
那是肇事逃逸
我在你这个年纪的时候 想做一个小提琴家
我申请了音乐学校 但是没有通过面试
面试官告诉我 我有一双外科医生的手…
…所以我改行学医
当一扇门关上…
…另一扇就会为你打开
你还年轻，可以找到新的目标
再见，贾斯丁
祝您生活愉快，威尔士医生
雷妮，亲爱的，对不起
- 又是一个不好弄的病人？ - 他们不都是这样吗
- 你认为他会起诉吗？ - 他没有证据
他活着，就应该谢我
发生了什么？
你还好吗？
让我们出去，快点！快点！
马上让我们出去， 马上！快点！快点！
- 救命！ - 救救我们！
够了
- 托我上去 - 好的
好，抓住我的手
我在一个飞行比赛时见过你
I see you in a uniform flying.
特别客串主演:约翰・格鲁夫
（斯摩维尔镇高中实习招聘会）
你考虑过加入空军吗？
Have you ever considered a career in the Air Force?
我会考虑的
I'll think about it.
客串主演:亚当・布罗迪
你在笑什么？
What are you smiling about?
神川宏奈幸
I landed a summer job at Mayor Siegel's working on his re-election campaign.
我参加了西格尔市长再次竞选的暑期活动
我以为你会去法院帮你妈妈的忙
I thought you were helping your mom at the court.
唐娜・布洛克
罗斯女法官可以让堪萨斯州立大学的学生 帮她整理文件
Judge Ross can get some KSU students to schlep her files.
联合执行制片:格列哥・比曼
谁愿意暑假的时候跟着爸妈混？
Who wants to hang out with their parents all summer?
监督制片:马克・伏黑顿
- 也是 - 对不起，不是说你，克拉克
-Yeah. -Sorry, Clark.
你注意到在空军招生摊那边 关校长的儿子了吗？
Did you notice Kwan's son down at the Air Force booth?
制片:迈克尔・格林
他是跟着关校长长大的 空军学校就像地中海俱乐部那么爽
Growing up with Kwan, the Air Force would seem like Club Med.
制片:道里斯・伊根
- 哇，你看上去很不错 - 谢谢，我是为了见面试官的
-Wow, you look nice. -Thanks, I was going for professional.
联合制片:格雷格・沃克
你知道《星球日报》只选四个高中实习生吗？
Did you know the Daily Planet only takes four high school interns from the state?
- 你是常胜将军，克罗伊 - 那你告诉他啊
-You're a shoo-in, Chloe. -Tell him that.
他们去年接了500多份申请呢
He said they received over 500 applicants last year.
- 我怀疑我有没有机会参加面试 - 还有《询查报》呢
-I doubt I'll get an interview. -There's always the Inquisitor.
- 莱克斯没把你勾引过去吗？ - 没，我更想参加《星球日报》的面试
-Didn't Lex offer to hook you up? -I'm interning at the Planet.
联合执行制片:肯・霍顿
I don't care if it's delivering coffee.
只要能去那边，让我去端咖啡也愿意
你周六去大都会时可以再试试
Why don't you try again Saturday when you're in Metropolis?
编剧:菲利普・莱温斯 阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
你为什么要去大都会？
Why are you going to Metropolis?
是我们要去大都会，克拉克
We're going to Metropolis, Clark.
导演:詹姆斯・马歇尔
有学生记者会啊，你忘了？
The student journalism conference?
不是由你替我们报名吗，别说你忘了 因为现在报名已经太晚了
You were supposed to sign us up. I know you didn't forget. It's too late to get in.
抱歉，我这周一直在塔龙 跟拉娜做一个历史课题
Sorry. I've been at the Talon all week with Lana working on a history project.
- 别的事情都不重要了 - 喂，不是那样的
-Everything else becomes less important. -Whoa, that's not true.
我们这三个星期一起相处的时间有多少？
How much time have we spent together in three weeks?
- 我们每天都见面啊 - 只有45分钟，还是因为我的车坏了…
-We see each other every day. -It was 45 minutes. My car broke down...
…在塔龙外面，你得载我回家
...outside the Talon and you gave me a ride home.
- 我难道必须把你从拉娜那抢过来吗 - 你不觉得你有点不讲理吗？
-I had to tear you away from Lana. -Don't you think you're being unfair?
不！只要莱克斯和拉娜在 别人对你就都不重要了
No! Whenever Lex and Lana are around, no one else exists.
等等，克罗伊，你怎么变得这么敏感？
Wait, Chloe, why are you being so hypersensitive?
虽然有不少男人是火星男 可你真是比火星男还火星
Most men are from Mars, but you're from a distant galaxy I've never heard of.
是我做错了，但克罗伊干嘛这么激动？
I know I screwed up, but why is Chloe having a breakdown?
- 你真不会观察人啊 - 这话什么意思？
-You're not the most observant person. -What are you talking about?
她想跟你单独呆一天，没有拉娜和莱克斯 她想跟你去春季舞会
She wanted to spend a day with you. She was gonna ask you to the spring formal.
是，但是那有点像…
Yeah, but that'd be like....
约会？
Date?
也许你摘下盯着拉娜的眼罩 你会发现克罗伊喜欢你
Maybe if you took off your Lana blinders, you'd realize Chloe likes you.
克拉克，我没兴趣听你道歉
Clark, I'm not interested in an apology.
- 不是我想像中的欢迎，嗨 - 嘿！
-Not the welcome I was expecting, hi. -Hey!
你还好吗？真高兴见到你 你什么时候回来的？
How are you? It's good to see you. When did you get back?
昨天，我只是顺道过来 谢谢你发给我那些邮件
Yesterday. I just wanted to thank you, by the way, for sending all those emails.
- 它们陪我走过了那段困难时期 - 我相信很多人都有跟你保持联系吧
-They got me through a tough time. -I'm sure lots of people kept in touch.
其实我多数朋友不见面就不会想起我
For most of my friends, it was out of sight, out of mind.
我知道那种感觉 那么你什么时候重新开始画卡通？
I know the feeling. So when can you start drawing your cartoon again?
大家都在期待火光鸟的更多冒险
Everybody's been waiting for the further adventures of the flaming crow's feet.
不幸的是我的手恐怕不行了
Unfortunately my drawing hand's kind of shot.
- 噢，抱歉 - 没关系
-Oh, I'm sorry. -It's okay.
我正在重新评估我的未来
I'm in the process of re-evaluating my life.
听着，我可不可以请你喝杯咖啡…
So listen, is there any chance that maybe I could buy you a cup of coffee...
…或者你喜欢的那种脱脂无泡拿铁？
...or one of those nonfat, no-foam lattes that you like?
好啊，为什么不呢？ 我也在重新评估我的未来
Yeah, why not? I'm in the process of re-evaluating my life too.
我们走
Let's go.
（莉莉安・卢瑟 爱妻与慈母，1951-1993年）
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
我来这的原因跟你一样
I'm here for the same reason you are.
- 今天是她的忌日 - 九年了
-The anniversary of her death. -It's been nine years.
为什么突然多愁善感了？
Why the sudden burst of sentimentality?
我应得的，该从你的生活中消失
I deserve that, just disappearing from your life.
我相信我母亲在卢瑟集团的股份 也帮你做了决定
I'm sure all that LuthorCorp stock my mother left you helped.
是你父亲这样告诉你的？
Is that what your father told you?
那些年我曾经以为你爱我
All those years I thought you loved me.
原来你只是为了钱
But you were just in it for the money.
我知道你很生气，你有权利生气 但我们得谈谈
I know you're angry and you have every right to be, but we need to talk.
我相信，我对你要说的完全没兴趣
I can't believe there's anything you'd say that would interest me.
再见，帕梅拉
Goodbye, Pamela.
这是我最喜欢的连环漫画之一
This one's my favorite strip.
- 真的吗 - 是的
-Really. -Yes.
嗨，两位
Hey, guys.
- 嗨 - 你认识的贾斯丁
-Hey. -You know Justin.
当然，欢迎回来，感觉怎么样
Yeah. Of course, welcome back. How are you feeling?
就是逐渐去适应它
Oh, just kind of taking it one day at a time.
他们找到撞到你的司机了没？
Did they find the driver who hit you?
没有，我能给警察的线索也不多 很长时间以来我都毫无印象
No. No, I couldn't give the police much. I didn't remember anything for a long time.
你记起什么了吗？
Well, what do you remember?
- 一小部分，记得车牌是DDI. - 我们应该从这部分着手调查
-A little bit of the license plate. DDI. -Well, we should look into it.
- 打电话给警察 - 如果我们找到些线索，就会给警方的
-Call the police. -lf we find something, we'll pass it on.
好
Okay.
好了，我刚和莱克斯谈论过了 他给我们留了两张记者大会的票
Anyway, I talked to Lex. He scored us two tickets to the conference.
别担心，贾斯丁已经报名了 所以我可以作为他的伴一起去
Don't worry about it. Justin's signed up so I'm going as his guest.
- 或许我们大家都可以一起去 - 不必了
-Yeah, or we could all go together. -No.
反正克拉克对新闻业一点也没有兴趣
Clark's not that interested in journalism anyway.
好的，我也应该走了，听着…
Right, okay. I should probably get going, listen--
谢谢
Thank you.
- 嗨 - 嗨，克拉克，你妈妈在家吗?
-Hi. -Hey, Clark. Is your mom around?
（下楼时，医生在意外事故中失去双手）
谢谢
- 嗨 - 嘿，克拉克，你妈妈在吗？
- 我想订购一些馅饼 - 她在上课，我来帮你
-I wanted to order more of her pies. -She's in class, I can help you.
我还以为你会帮克罗伊校对最终版本
I thought you'd be helping Chloe proof the latest edition.
- 有人帮她了 - 你俩还在冷战？
-She had enough help. -Are you two still fighting?
谁说我们在冷战？
Who said we were fighting?
我昨天在实习会上看到，你们俩到底怎么了？
Kind of caught it yesterday at the career fair. What's going on with you two?
克罗伊喜欢我
Chloe likes me.
那你对她感觉是怎样？
So how do you feel about her?
感觉也有点超过了朋友界限
Like maybe we could be more than friends.
- 我看到她和贾斯丁在一起，我有点… - 吃醋？
-I saw her with Justin. I got kind of-- -Jealous?
就好像突然发现了答案 然后一切感觉都因此改变了
It's like you find out this secret and it colors everything.
我不敢相信以前居然没发现
Just can't believe I never saw it before.
有时最适合你的人就在你的眼前 但你却往往不能发现
Sometimes the right person can be in front of your eyes and you never know.
- 你要多少馅饼？ - 一打
-So how many pies did you want? -A dozen.
惠特尼怎么样啦？我听说他的父亲感觉好多了
How's Whitney? I hear his dad's feeling better.
他很好
He's great.
一切都很好吗？
Everything okay?
从来没这么好
Never better.
好运，我希望你和克罗伊的事顺利
Good luck. I hope things work out with Chloe.
我也是
Me too.
再见
Bye.
该死
Damn it.
皮特
Pete.
- 嗨 - 嗨，看到克罗伊了没？
-Hey. -Hey, you seen Chloe?
英文课后就没见到， 她可能和贾斯丁在一起
Not since English. She's probably hanging out with Justin.
- 你觉得那家伙怎么样？ - 他看起来相当酷
-What do you think about that guy? -He seems pretty cool.
以前跟他不熟，他老是埋头画画
Never got to know him that well before, he was always buried in a sketchpad.
克罗伊似乎也喜欢他
Chloe seems to like him.
小心一点，克拉克，你听起来有点吃醋啊
Careful, Clark, you almost sound a little jealous.
我不是吃醋，我只是关心
I'm not jealous, I'm concerned.
为什么，只是因为克罗伊喜欢上了一个好男生？ 这也使我很担忧啊
Why, because Chloe's falling for a nice guy? It's got me worried too.
看
Look.
昨天贾斯丁的档案袋里放着这个
Justin had this in his portfolio yesterday.
下楼时，医生因意外事故失去双手
"Going Down. Doctor Loses Hands in Freak Accident."
- 那又怎么样 - 那就是贾斯丁的医生
-So? -That was Justin's doctor.
他带着这种剪报，你不觉得奇怪吗？
Don't you think it's weird he's carrying that?
我喜欢收集讽刺性的悲剧意外
I liked the tragic irony.
你总喜欢在背后说别人坏话？
You always talk about people behind their backs?
- 贾斯丁，我不是这个意思… - 是的，你就是
-Justin, I didn't mean-- -Yes, you did.
我刚开始和克罗伊呆在一起 你就注意到了她的存在，然后想我退出吗？
I start spending time with Chloe, suddenly you realize she exists and want me out?
- 克罗伊和我只是朋友 - 你本来有机会和她在一起的
-Chloe and I are just friends. -You had your chance with her.
现在该把机会给我了
Now you let me have mine.
你究竟在这干嘛
What the hell are you doing here?
我想看看你会成长为什么样的人
I wanted to see what kind of young man you'd grown into.
一个很忙的人
A very busy one.
那如果没别的事…
So if there's nothing else--
我们曾经很亲密，亚历山大（莱克斯名字） 你以前就像我的儿子一样
We were close once, Alexander, you were like a son to me.
你只是个雇员，你领薪水来照顾我
You were an employee. You were paid to watch me while...
因为我母亲生病，我父亲为事业全世界到处跑
...my mother's health failed and my father crisscrossed the globe on business.
我爱你像爱我自己的儿子一样
I loved you like my own.
流星雨事件过后，我是唯一没把你当异类的人
After the meteor shower, I was the one who never looked at you differently.
就算你曾在低谷时支持过我
Just because you knew me at a vulnerable point...
也没有权力在离开十年后再走入我的生活
...doesn't give you the right to waltz back in a decade later.
一切都变了，我变了，你想从我这得到什么？
Things have changed. I've changed. What do you want from me?
我想让你知道究竟发生了什么？
I want you to know what really happened.
- 你违背了对我母亲临终前的誓言 - 不，我没有
-You lied to my mother on her deathbed. -No, I didn't.
我很想留下来，但你父亲把我赶走了
I had every intention of staying, but your father sent me away.
葬礼过后，他把我叫到他的办公室，告诉我
After the funeral, he called me into his office and told me...
如果我再跟你联系，他会剥夺你的继承权
...if I ever had contact with you again that he would disinherit you.
他为什么要这么做？
Why would he do that?
因为他想让你变得像他，而不是像她
Because he wanted you to be his son, not hers.
那你现在又为什么出现？
So why show up now?
我父亲的威胁时效到期了吗？
Does the statute of limitations on my father's threat expire?
我想知道，是否无论莱诺如何影响你
I needed to see if you'd found a way to be true to yourself...
你依然能坚持自己的路
...in spite of Lionel's efforts.
而且老实说，我想得到你的原谅
And to be honest, I wanted your forgiveness.
那恐怕你自己都很难相信吧
I'm afraid you'll have to find a way to grant it to yourself.
再见，亚历山大
Goodbye, Alexander.
我希望店里的东西 都像你母亲的有机苹果馅饼一样卖得畅销
I wish everything sold as well as your mom's organic apple pies.
- 滴水汇成河 - 嗨，克拉克
-Every little bit helps. -Hey, Clark.
- 嗨，惠特尼，你父亲怎么样了？ - 在好转中，回家真开心
-Hey, Whitney, how's your dad? -On the mend. Happy to be home.
嗨，把周六晚上腾空出来
Hey. Keep Saturday night free.
我有两张在大都会剧场上映的 《我们的小镇》的戏票
Got two tickets to Our Town at the Metropolis Playhouse.
- 哇，怎么突然想到买的 - 看见你在学校看海报
-Wow. What inspired you to do that? -Saw you reading it at school.
我想弥补一些我们之间错过的时间
Thought I might start making up for some lost time.
- 再见 - 再见
-See you. -Bye.
惠特尼在过去的两个礼拜 比以往一整年都更加关注我
Whitney has paid more attention to me in the last two weeks than he has all year.
你跟他沟通过了吗？
Have you talked to him about it?
他父亲好转后，他开心多了
He's seemed so happy ever since his dad got better.
- 他想把我们错失的快乐都找回来 - 那你觉得呢？
-He wants to pick up where we left off. -How do you feel about that?
佛得曼先生病了之后，惠特尼就很需要我
After Mr. Fordman got sick, Whitney needed me.
那时我们的关系有点被重新定位了 现在又得再定位回去
Kind of defined our relationship. Now we need to redefine it.
需要重新定位的关系很多
There's a lot of that going on.
- 你和克罗伊那边怎么样？ - 还拖着呢
-How are things with Chloe? -Unresolved.
你要怎么做？
What are you gonna do?
没想好，我怕和她交往不成 会连朋友也不能再做
I don't know, just don't want to lose a friend in the process.
一旦越过那条界限，就没法再回头
Once you've crossed that line, you can't go back.
克罗伊也跟我说过这句话 不过那时我们在讨论另一个人
Chloe gave that same advice about someone else.
后来怎么样了？
What happened?
- 我决定和那个人保持朋友关系 - 你后悔过那样的决定吗？
-Decided to stay friends. -Do you regret that decision?
是的，我让某一刻溜走，再也找不回
Yeah. I let that moment slip away and I don't think I'll ever get it back.
这次我不想在克罗伊身上犯同样的错误
I don't want to make that same mistake twice.
我刚才把你想起的肇事车那部分车牌号
Hey. I just emailed the partial license plate details of your hit-and-run...
邮件给我在车管局的线人，让他查查本郡的车
...to my contact at the DMV. I told him to start with cars in the county.
他说有了消息就会传真给我
He said that he would fax me whatever information he found.
哇
Wow.
送给你，这个花了我一整夜时间
Oh, here, it took me all night.
噢，哇
Oh, wow.
- 真好看 - 你也是
-It's beautiful. -Well, so are you.
你知道吗，那辆车撞了我之后 我躺在路上…
Did you know that after that car hit me and I was lying in the road...
- 脑子里都是你的样子 - 我？为什么是我？
-...I kept picturing your face? -Me? Why me?
因为我一直非常喜欢你
Because I always had the biggest crush on you.
可是我没勇气表白 后来那时我以为自己快死了
And I was too afraid to do anything. I thought, here I am about to die...
永远也没机会说出口了
...and I'm never gonna get the chance to tell her how I feel.
但后来在医院里，你又发邮件给我
But when you started emailing me when I was in the hospital...
我感觉到那是我的第二次机会 我不能再放弃你
...I knew that this was my chance and I wasn't going to let you get away twice.
我坚持抗争都是为了你
I fought my way back for you.
出什么事了？
What just happened?
- 你愿意开放思维听我说吗？ - 当然
-Can you keep an open mind? -Sure.
事故过后我出了点事
Something happened to me after the accident...
在医院时，我发现自己可以凭意念…
...and when I was in the hospital I found that I could move things.
- 使物品移动 - 摄神取物那类的？
-With my mind. -Like telekinesis?
把你吓着了吗？
Am I freaking you out?
信不信由你，比这更怪的事我也见过
Believe it or not, I have seen stranger things.
因为我不想被你放到“怪异之墙”上
Because I don't want to end up on your wall.
别担心，不会的 我们再让东西飘起来好不好
Don't worry, you won't. Now, let's make everything float again.
嘿，克罗伊，我能…？
Hey, Chloe, can l--?
- 能不能到外面和你谈谈？ - 当然，好，克拉克
-Can I talk to you outside for a second? -Yeah, sure, Clark.
- 我很快回来 - 好的
-I'll be right back. -Okay.
（找到相符车牌）
你不觉得你和贾斯丁进展太快点了？
Don't you think this Justin thing is moving a little too fast?
我们互通邮件六个月了 我对他比对你了解都多
We've been emailing for six months. I know him better than I know you.
- 他跟你说过他医生发生的事吗？ - 没有
-Did he say what happened to his doctor? -No.
他倒是说过你在背后对他说三道四
But he did tell me that you were talking about him behind his back.
- 我只是想照看你，克罗伊 - 你这是怎么了，克拉克？
-I was just looking out for you, Chloe. -What's with you, Clark?
你是不是有什么救世主情结啊？
Do you have some savior complex?
我有危险你就来救我，但其他时候你就正眼也不看我
If I'm in trouble you'll rescue me. Other than that you're emotionally unavailable.
我只是不希望你因为生我的气 才和贾斯丁搅合在一起
I just don't want you getting involved with Justin because you're mad at me.
你爱信不信，克拉克，我的世界不是全围着你转
Believe it or not, Clark, my world does not revolve around you.
你为何就不能接受，我已经找到一个特别的人
Why can't you accept that I've found someone special...
而且不像你，我愿意为爱冒险
...and unlike you, I'm willing to take a chance?
告诉我，欺骗大家很容易吗？
Just tell me one thing, was it easy to lie to everybody?
- 贾斯丁，你在这做什么？ - 回想一些忘记的事
-Justin? What are you doing here? -Reliving old memories.
你该回家了
I think you should go home.
我过马路时只走了一半，就被你的车冲倒
I was only halfway across the crosswalk when your car came barreling around.
撞得太严重了，我简直觉得自己裂成了两半
Hit me so hard, it felt like I'd been broken in half.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我还记得自己躺在街上，血滴进眼睛
I remember lying in the street, blood dripping into my eyes...
看着你的尾灯渐行渐远 你根本没有费心停下来看看
...watching your taillights disappear. You didn't even bother to stop.
不是我
It wasn't me.
我从在医院里就能这样了
It started in the hospital.
得到这种超能力，算是弥补我双手失去的力量
Maybe as a way to compensate for the motor skills I'd lost in my hands.
我当时全身都被固定
I was immobilized in a total body cast.
然后突然发现自己凭意念就可以移动物体
Then I found that I could move things just by thinking.
可这样也不能真正补偿我所失去的
But that didn't replace what I'd lost.
没有任何事可以取代我的画
Because nothing could ever do that.
贾斯丁，停手！
Justin, stop it!
你知道被2000磅的车撞到是什么滋味吗？
Do you know what it feels like to be hit by a 2000-pound car?
嘿，莱克斯，这么晚来干嘛？
Hey, Lex, what are you doing here so late?
（男人来自火星，女人来自金星）
和你父母谈谈补偿的问题，你在读什么？
Came to talk to your parents about the settlement. What are you reading?
男人来自金星，女人来自火星？
Men are From Mars, Women are From Venus?
我是想了解一下女生的心理
I'm trying to get an insight into the female psyche.
我很怀疑你看书就能了解她们，有什么问题了？
I seriously doubt you'll find it in here. What's the problem?
我有两个很棒的朋友，偏偏都是女孩
I've got these two amazing friends who both happen to be girls.
为方便讨论起见 我们就把她们称为拉娜和克罗伊吧
For argument's sake, let's call them Lana and Chloe.
我一直喜欢拉娜，但我没法接近她
I've always liked Lana, but I could never get near her.
我发现克罗伊喜欢我，我好像也对她有感觉
I found out that Chloe likes me, I may have feelings for her too.
你现在想追哪一个？
Which one do you want to pursue?
我想保护好两边的友谊
I want to protect my friendship with both.
那你哪个也追不到了
Then you'll never get either one.
多谢了，我还是回头看书吧
Thanks. Think I'll stick with the book.
克拉克，爱本来就不是安全的 想爱就要冒险
Clark, love isn't about playing it safe, it's about risks.
不想冒险，也就不会知道结果
Unless you put yourself out there, you'll never know.
- 你曾经爱过吗？ - 我这辈子只爱过两个女人
-Have you ever been in love before? -I've only loved two women in my life.
- 一个已经死了，另一个又背叛了我 - 很遗憾
-One died and the other betrayed me. -I'm sorry.
有些人注定要独自活着
Some people are meant to be alone.
- 妈，怎么了？ - 是关校长
-Mom, what is it? -It's Principal Kwan.
他发生了事故，死了
He was killed in an accident.
- 嘿，各位，都还好吗？ - 我依然不能相信发生了这种事
-Hey, guys. How are you holding up? -I still can't believe this happened.
正收集悼念材料，可是要用的照片
Putting together a memorial issue but when you're looking for pictures...
总是找不到，皮特，你能不能再查查图书馆档案？
...you never find them. Pete, can you check the library files? One more time?
- 当然 - 谢谢
-Sure. -Thank you.
看到关校长事故的警方报告了 车还没熄火，应该是不小心撞档了
Got Kwan's police report. His car was still on, it must have slipped into gear.
- 克罗伊，你没事吗？ - 恩，没事
-Chloe, are you okay? -Yeah, I'm fine.
- 这个办公室里什么都找不到！ - 让我帮忙
-I can't find anything in this office! -Let me help.
不用，谢谢你
No, thank you.
克罗伊，看这个
Chloe, look at this.
关校长车牌号的前三位 和撞到贾斯丁又逃逸的那辆车一样
The first three numbers of Kwan's license plate match Justin's hit-and-run driver.
- 那能推断出什么，克拉克？ - 那么…
-What are you getting at? -Well...
…看起来很多奇怪的事故都和这家伙有关系
...there's a lot of weird accidents around this guy.
克拉克，你完全是弄错人了
Clark, you are seriously barking up the wrong tree here.
你有没有收到车管局发过来的传真啊？
Did you get a response from the DMV?
- 没有，根本就没传过来。 - 不，那边传给你了
-No, it never came through. -Yes, you did.
昨天下午4:43传来的 就是你和贾斯丁在这儿的那会儿
4:43 yesterday. Around the time you were here with Justin.
- 他不可能干出这种事情 - 为什么，就因为你喜欢他？
-He couldn't have done it. -Because you like him?
不是，因为我了解他，他不会伤害任何人
No, because I know him and I know he wouldn't hurt anyone.
真希望你是对的
I hope you're right.
“我庆祝我自己，歌唱我自己， 我承担的你也将承担”
"I celebrate myself and what I assume you shall assume."
“因为属于我的每一个原子也同样属于你”
"For every atom belonging to me as good belongs to you."
听起来像是描述家庭，对吧？
Sounds like a description of family, doesn't it?
不是我们这样的家庭，什么时候开始读诗了？
Not ours. Since when do you read poetry?
我们要卖掉卡德摩斯实验室，莱克斯
We're selling Cadmus Labs, Lex.
但我持有50%的股份，而且具有否决权。
Our deal memo gives me 50 percent ownership with veto rights.
这件事你还没问过我的意见
I don't recall you asking my opinion.
我们当初买它只是为了搞垮哈里爵士的
We only bought Cadmus to bankrupt Sir Harry.
自从我们大量转手股票之后， 那个公司已经没别的价值
After we pumped and dumped the stock, the company's worthless.
它的使命已经完成了
It served its purpose.
你专程来这不只为了谈卡德摩斯实验室吧
You didn't come all this way to talk about Cadmus.
我知道帕梅拉已经回来了
I understand Pamela's back in the States.
- 并且她也见过你了 - 那么你是来撤销我的继承权的？
-And that she paid you a visit. -Did you come to disinherit me?
- 她这样告诉你的？ - 是不是真的？
-Is that what she told you? -Is it true?
你妈妈是一个很不同凡响的女人
Your mother was an extraordinary woman.
但她找助手的眼光还不够好，帕梅拉很会钻营
But her taste in help left a lot to be desired. Pamela was a hanger-on.
她说服你妈妈把所有的股票留给她，然后…
She convinced your mother to leave her all that stock, then...
…你妈妈尸骨未寒，她就消失了
...she disappeared before the body was even cold.
你百忙之中过来就是为了告诉我这个？
You took time out of your busy schedule to tell me that?
我知道她对你来说很重要 但我不希望她利用感情牌…
I know how much she meant to you and I don't want her using emotional tyranny...
- …来骗取你的钱。 - 她为什么会那么做？
-...to hit you up for money. -Why would she do that?
她已经有很多股票了啊
She's got plenty of stock.
可能是她不想卖了它们来支付她的医疗费
Probably she doesn't want to sell it to pay her medical bills.
什么医疗费？
What medical bills?
- 她没告诉你么，真是伟大啊 - 告诉我什么啊？
-She didn't tell you. How noble. -Tell me what?
她快不行了，莱克斯，得了癌症
She's dying, Lex. Cancer.
也许是这些年总在圣特罗佩晒日光浴造成的
Probably all those years sitting in the sun in Saint-Tropez.
- 她来找你干嘛？ - 求得原谅
-What does she want? -Forgiveness.
那你跟她怎么说的？
And what did you tell her?
滚出去
To get out.
看来她对你不是很了解，我说得没错吧？
No. She doesn't know you very well, does she?
你来这儿干嘛？
What are you doing in here?
丹尼，对于你爸爸的事，我很遗憾
Danny, I'm really sorry about what happened to your dad.
我不明白到底怎么回事儿 车钥匙明明在他身上啊
I don't understand what happened. He had the car keys with him.
看起来就像有什么东西推着车子， 狠狠地朝他撞了去
It's like something just smashed the car right into him.
丹尼，你知道一个叫贾斯丁・基恩斯的人么？
Danny, did you know a Justin Gaines?
他昨天晚上有没有来过这儿？
Do you know if he came by here last night?
不知道，怎么了？
No, why?
我觉得贾斯丁也许认为 你父亲是他车祸的肇事人
I think Justin believes your father was responsible for the accident.
那太扯了，你该走了
That's crazy. You should leave.
他比对了你父亲和肇事逃跑的车牌号 结果发现有一部分是一样的
He matched part of your dad's license plate to the hit-and-run driver's.
有没有可能贾斯丁的推断是对的？
Is there a chance Justin's right?
我父亲不该这样没命
My dad didn't deserve this.
你父亲不是那个肇事者，对么？
Your dad wasn't the one driving the car, was he?
是你撞了他
You're the one who hit Justin.
我爸爸…
My dad...
…他只是想保护我
...he was just trying to protect me.
克罗伊？
Chloe?
（威尔士医生，贾斯丁・基恩斯）
（为了正义）
- 我妈妈说你在这儿 - 哦，我本来想给你个惊喜的
-My mom said you were here. -Oh, I wanted to surprise you.
今天一天没在学校看到你 关校长的事儿你听说了么？
I didn't see you at school today. Did you hear about Principal Kwan?
- 听说了，真是很奇怪，对吧？ - 是啊
-I did. That's really weird, right? -Yeah.
我想我们自己永远都想不到哪天就挂了
I guess you never know when your time's up.
所以我们应该好好利用现有的时光
Which is why I think we should make the most of the time that we have.
- 怎么了？ - 没什么，我给忘了，突然想起来…
-What's the matter? -Nothing. I forgot, I just remembered...
…我约了克拉克在他家见面的
...I told Clark I'd meet him at his house.
你已经拒绝他了 还有必要在他身上花费那么多时间么
For someone that is out of the picture, you sure spend a lot of time with him.
别多想，今天我就是去跟他说清楚 我们俩现在的关系的
Don't worry. Today I plan on telling him exactly what's going on between us.
你做得很对，克拉克，说服了丹尼去自首
You did the right thing, Clark. Convincing Danny to turn himself in.
（读诗会，周四夜）
- 他父亲已经死了，现在他也可能要坐牢 - 某些秘密能毁掉整个家庭啊
-His father's dead. He's going to jail. -Some secrets destroy families.
克拉克，克罗伊的电话，她听起来吓坏了
Clark, Chloe's on the phone, she sounds really freaked out.
- 克罗伊，怎么了？ - 克拉克，我到处打电话找你
-Chloe, what's up? -I've been calling all over the place.
我真是糊涂了，贾斯汀有牵连，你是对的
I really screwed up, Justin is involved, you were right.
- 冷静点，你在哪儿？ -在你家谷仓里
-Well, calm down. Where are you? -In your barn.
我之前没有对你说实话，克拉克
I haven't been completely honest with you, Clark.
我知道贾斯丁怎么能制造这样的事故
I know how Justin caused those accidents.
克罗伊？克罗伊！
Chloe? Chloe!
贾斯丁？
Justin?
你怎么能背叛我？你怎么能背叛我们俩的幸福？
How could you betray me? How could you betray what we had together?
哦，不要！
Oh, no!
我喜欢你的就是这一点，克罗伊，你是个斗士
That's what I love about you, Chloe. You're a fighter.
对不起，我也不想让事情这样结局
I'm sorry. I didn't want it to end like this.
- 你怎么做到的？ - 你杀错人了
-How did you do that? -You killed the wrong man.
- 你撒谎 - 他的儿子已经自首了
-You're lying. -His son just turned himself in.
- 他才是撞你的那个人 - 不可能
-He was the one who hit you. -That is not true!
你说过你在乎克罗伊 你究竟想害死多少无辜的人？
You said you cared about Chloe. How many people are you willing to kill?
多一个也不多
Just one more.
你真应该好好把这些楼梯平台修修了，克拉克
You've really got to stick those landings, Clark.
你赢不了的，贾斯丁
You can't win, Justin.
克罗伊，你没事儿吧？
Chloe, are you okay?
- 真没想到你会来看我 - 为什么不早点告诉我呢？
-You're the last person I expected. -Why didn't you tell me?
- 这跟你没关系 - 你都快不行了，还说和我没关系？
-It's not your concern. -It's not my concern that you're dying?
- 我能帮上忙，我能帮你治疗 - 我不是来祈求你的帮助或怜悯什么的…
-I could help, I can get you treatment. -I didn't come to you for help or pity...
…我来是因为我已经没有什么可失去的了
...I came because I have nothing left to lose.
事实上，我很惭愧 癌症扩散了之后，我才有这个勇气
The truth is, I'm ashamed that it took metastasizing to give me the courage.
我让那个混蛋威胁了我这么长时间
I let that bastard frighten me into submission for so long.
由于太害怕，甚至一次都不敢跟你说 你对我来说是多么重要
I was too scared to even tell you just once how much you mean to me.
我是多么希望，你成长的时候，有我在身边
How much I wanted to help you grow up.
我也希望你能够 那样我会成长为一个更好的人
I wish you had. I might be a better man.
事实上，你能来，就已经表示出你的为人
The fact that you're here speaks volumes about the man that you are.
你母亲肯定会很自豪
Your mother would be proud.
- 我很想念她 - 我也是
-I really miss her. -So do I.
（周末短诗，购物赠搭讪名言）
- 我刚和贾斯丁的父母谈过 - 他怎么样？
-I just spoke to Justin's parents. -How's he doing?
他在精神病房，警方还不知道以什么罪名起诉他…
He's in the psychiatric ward. The police don't know what to charge him with...
…但至少他不可能再伤害到别人了
...but at least he won't hurt anybody.
那现在是你批评我“早就告诉过你了”之类的 还是我自己给自己检讨就算了
So should we do the "I told you so" part or is my perennial bad judgment implicit?
克罗伊，我也希望我是错的
Chloe, I wish I were wrong.
我到底是怎么了？ 我能够看穿老远之外的很奇怪的事情…
What is it with me? I can spot Wall of Weird material from a mile away...
…但当事情发生在我跟前时，我却糊涂了
...but put it in front of me and I'm oblivious.
你不是糊涂，你这是信任
You're not oblivious, you're trusting.
你心里足够强大，愿意为感情冒险
You're strong enough to take risks with your emotions.
我真希望能够像你一样勇敢
I wish I were as brave as you.
那两张去记者大会的票我还拿着
I still have those tickets to the journalism convention.
这对我们来说是个很不错的共处的机会
It'd be a good chance for us to spend some time together.
好的，就算约会了
Okay, it's a date.
惠特尼，我们需要谈谈
Whitney, we need to talk.
怎么了？出什么事了？
What is it? What happened?
我父亲去世了
It's my dad.